<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xml[
<!ENTITY ndash '&#8211;'>
<!ENTITY mdash '&#8212;'>
<!ENTITY lsquo "&#8216;">
<!ENTITY rsquo "&#8217;">
<!ENTITY ldquo '&#8220;'>
<!ENTITY rdquo '&#8221;'>
<!ENTITY amp '&#38;'>
]>
<item
	id="japethan_hammer"
	xmlns="https://github.com/dwugofski/p2e" 
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="../../../templates/items/item.xsd">

	<name>Japethan Hammer</name>
	<level>7</level>
	<traits>
		<trait type="rarity">unique</trait>
		<trait type="equipment">intelligent</trait>
		<trait type="school">evocation</trait>
		<trait type="general">magical</trait>
	</traits>
	<price>
		<int>3250</int>
		<money>gp</money>
	</price>
	<usage>
		<held>1</held>
	</usage>
	<bulk>1</bulk>
	<description>
		<p>A legendary weapon destined to be held by a champion of Nibarell, the Japethan Hammer is a work of wonder crafted by the god of craftsmen himself. It is a sophisticated yet durable contraption, decorated with ornate motifs blending the styles of dwarven and elvish design, much like most crafts associated with Nibarell and his worshippers.</p>
		<p>This weapon is a +1 magical weapon which can be used as either a sickle or a hammer. In either form, the weapon&rsquo;s damage die is 1d8, though the type of damage depends on the form (slashing for the sickle and bludgeoning for the hammer).</p>
		<p>Additionally, the Japethan Hammer contains the consciousness of Japethan, the legendary advisor to Nibarell. Consulting with Japethan bestows a +3 item bonus to checks involving his areas of expertise, which are mainly Crafting, Dwarven Lore, and Nibarell Lore. Japethan himself is an absent-minded old man, only half occupying the hammer and half consulting with business in Nibarell.</p>
		<activate>
			<action>
				<act_count>1</act_count>
				<name>Interact</name>
			</action>
			<effect>
				<p>Switch the form of the weapon between a hammer and a sickle. In either form, the weapon&rsquo;s damage die is 1d8, though the type of damage depends on the form (slashing for the sickle and bludgeoning for the hammer).</p>
			</effect>
		</activate>
	</description>
</item>